Alex Clark



About

Alex Clark is a **Python Web Developer** from Baltimore, Maryland, USA living in Bethesda, Maryland. He has a **Bachelor of Science in Computer Science** from Loyola University in Maryland and has worked as a **Network Engineer, Software Engineer, Systems Administrator** and **Technical Team Leader** since May, 1998. He is also the **President of DC Python**, a non-profit organization he co-founded to promote and support the use of Python software in DC.

Work Experience

ACLARK.NET, LLC

Partner, Python Web Developer

May, 2004 — Present

http://aclark.net

- Develop, deploy, maintain and support Python web applications with Django, Plone, Pyramid and Zope.
- Dramatically transform cross-platform platforms after stand-alone "outside the box" thinking. Quickly repurpose open-source resources vis-a-vis functionalized partnerships. Enthusiastically revolutionize wireless testing procedures for diverse relationships.
- Intrinsicly unleash virtual e-markets after distinctive initiatives. Globally recaptiualize interoperable bandwidth for empowered web-readiness. Progressively administrate next-generation catalysts for change rather than ubiquitous content.

Neurophysiology Imaging Facility (NIF) \rightarrow Division of Intramural Research Programs (DIRP) \rightarrow National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH) \rightarrow National Institutes of Health (NIH)

Systems Administrator

March, 2013 — Present

http://www.nimh.nih.gov/labs-at-nimh/research-areas/research-support-services

- Evaluate and recommend hardware and software for purchase by NIF
- Install, configure and maintain hardware and software. Troubleshoot and resolve hardware and software problems
- Install, configure and maintain operating systems, web server, content management system, FTP server, directory services, file sharing services, revision control system, and backups Manage network and system security. Analyze network performance and access to public resources
- Provide desktop support to NIF staff, resolve productivity issues
- Provide liaison to NIH CIT on infrastructure and security related issues

Scientific and Statistical Computing Core (SSCC) \rightarrow Division of Intramural Research Programs (DIRP) \rightarrow National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH) \rightarrow National Institutes of Health (NIH)

May, 2002 — October, 2005

Systems Administrator

http://www.nimh.nih.gov/labs-at-nimh/research-areas/research-support-services

- Evaluate and recommend hardware for purchase by SSCC
- Install, configure and maintain hardware. Troubleshoot and resolve hardware problems
- Install, configure and maintain operating systems, web server, content management system, FTP server, directory services, file sharing services, revision control system, and tape backups Manage network and system security. Analyze network performance and access to public resources
- Provide desktop support to SSCC members, resolved productivity issues
- Provide liaison to NIH CIT on infrastructure and security related issues
- Manage content management system, provide instruction to SSCC members on how to add and edit content
- Design and implement new site technology
- Respond to and resolve web site issues for the SSCC and AFNI community

Genuity

Network Engineer

October, 1998 — November, 2001

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BBN Technologies

Developed Perl/Expect software to support configuration management of 2000+ Cisco 2511
Access Servers, Equinox Terminal Servers, and Cisco Catalyst 1900/2820 Ethernet Switches
Developed Perl/SNMP/CGI software to support configuration of TELCO settings on "Big Box"
access servers (more than 4 ingress T1s --Cisco 5400, Lucent APX 8000, Nortel CVX 1800)

- Installed and configured Debian Linux, Redhat Linux, Sun Microsystems Solaris Unix and Microsoft Windows workstations and servers.
- Configured NICs under Linux.
- Provided production operations support.
- Performed maintenance on Genuity AOLNet and DialLinx dial-up networks. Configured 2000+ Cisco Access Servers, Equinox Terminal Servers and Cisco Catalyst Ethernet Switches.
- Verified the successful negotiation of TCP, PPP, and L2TP protocols through dial-up connections between client programs and remote access servers. Diagnosed and resolved problems end to end.

Charm Net

Systems Administrator

January, 1998 — August, 1998

- Managed four BSDI Unix servers for over 2,000 users.
- Installed and configured DNS, NFS, Sendmail, Apache, INND and Dump/Restore.
- Installed and configured hardware and software for streaming FM radio.
- Installed and configured BSDI Unix servers and Windows workstations and servers.
- Provided production operations support.

Loyola University Maryland

Help Desk Consultant, Student Technician

August, 1996 — November, 1997

http://www.loyola.edu/department/technology-services

- Provided telephone and in-person technical support to students, faculty, and administrators.
- Performed installation, maintenance, and trouble-shooting of hardware and software in labs, offices, and dormitories.
- Installed and configured Sun Microsystems Solaris Unix, Slackware Linux, Redhat Linux and Microsoft Windows workstations and servers.
- Provided production operations support.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Loyola University Maryland

January, 1999